KIRAN KUMAR

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name KIRAN MOHAN KUMAR

Address Bautzner Strasse, 24, 01099, Dresden, Saxony, Germany

Telephone +4917675914311

Linkedin http://www.linkedin.com/in/kiranmkumar

E-mail Kiran.kumar@aalto.fi; Kiran_m_kumar@outlook.com

Git Repository https://bitbucket.org/kiranmkumar/codesnippets

SUMMARY

Intern @ SAP Future Factory, Dresden Germany

Pursuing Master's with focus on Networks and Data Communication

• 3 years' experience with Oracle India Private Limited as a Solutions Engineer

 Hands on experience in Service Oriented Architecture, RDBMS and and Cloud Applications

Excellent Presentation, analytical skills, quick learner and smart problem solving skills

Team player with good communication and inter-personal skills

EDUCATION

Master's

• 2013-2015*(Expected) Aalto University, Finland

Major Communication and Network Technology

Degree awarded Master of Science(Technology)

Bachelor's

2006-2010 Visvesvaraya Technological University, India

Major Telecommunication Engineering

Degree awarded Bachelor of Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• 11/2014 – 03/2015 Intern @ SAP Future factory

Job Title Intern

• Responsibilities Working on SAP IoT solutions for business processes and Hana Cloud Platform .

• 05/2014 – 10/2014 Research Assistant at Aalto University

Job Title Application Developer

• Responsibilities Worked on a solution to analyze network data using Core Java, Swing for the Netradar project

(https://www.netradar.org/).

• 09/2013 - 05/2014 Nokia Research Center and Aalto University, Finland

• Job Title Developer

Responsibilities
 I was part of the Product Development Project team working on Wireless Sensors and its

integration with textile. I am responsible for the communication between the Audrino board,

Sensors and the User Interface. http://pdp.fi/portfolio-items/plink-2013-14/

• 07/2010 – 08/2013

• Job Title

Oracle India Private Limited, India (3 Years)

Solutions Engineer

Responsibilities

- Worked as a PL/SQL, Java and web services application developer working on Oracle Fusion Middleware Technologies (Oracle SOA, BPEL, BAM), Database 10g,11g and Enterprise Cloud Applications
- Developed integrations by writing new Java classes or PL/SQL procedures to plug in the gap between different Oracle enterprise applications
- Experience in gathering project requirements, preparing functional and technical design document
- Was awarded 'Bravo' quarterly performance recognition award for the ability to learn and master new areas quickly

• 01/2010 – 04/2010 • Job Title Bharat Electronics Limited, India

Project Trainee

Responsibilities

Designed and developed a Control Unit to control the Signal Strength, Bitrate, SNR, CNR of the DVBS Receiver Unit using embedded C.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

MOTHER TONGUE

KANNADA (NATIVE PROFICIENCY)

OTHER LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (FULL PROFESSIONAL PROFICIENCY); HINDI; GERMAN(1A)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Networking: TCP/IP,DNS, HTTP

Programming Languages: XLM, Core Java, SQL

Scripting Languages: Python

Web Development: Web Services, HTML, JavaScript, Node JS Other Skills: DBMS, GIT, Microsoft Office, Bug DB, Eclipse, Netbeans

Test Tools: Jasmine, Mockstar Tools: Wireshark, SOAPUI

Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Windows, Backtrack

COURSES IN AALTO UNIVERSITY

•INTERNET TECHNOLOGIES (IOT)

•MOBILE CLOUD COMPUTING

•COMMUNICATION NETWORKS

•SECURITY IN COMMUNICATION PROTOCOLS
•INTRODUCTION TO SOFTWARE ENGINEERING
•NETWORK APPLICATION FRAMEWORK

•ROUTING IN COMMUNICATION NETWORKS

•USER ORIENTED DESIGN OF NETWORKED SYSTEMS

RESEARCH INTERESTS

LTE, IOT, Security, Mobile Cloud Computing, Mobile/Web Development

^{**}References available on demand